The Argo program constitutes
a fundamental piece
inside the Global Ocean
Observing System,
and it is a joint initiative
of over 30 countries.
It is sponsored by the World
Meteorological Organization,
the Intergovernmental
Oceanographic Commission,
the International
Science Council
and the United Nations
Environment Program
Argo contributes to the
Climate Variability
and Predictability
Experiment project,
whose mission is to enable
a better understanding
of climate to the
benefit of society
and the environment
in which we live.
Argo is also a major contributor
to the Global Ocean Data
Assimilation Experiment,
whose mission is to improve
global and regional ocean
analysis and forecasting systems.
Overall coordination
is provided through
the Argo Information Center,
an office associated to the World
Meteorological Organization
and the Intergovernmental
Oceanographic Commission.
Each country that finances the
network does so voluntarily,
making the data obtained
freely available.