The core mission
of the Argo program
was to provide a real time
improvement in capacity
and measurement of temperature
and salinity across
the first 2000 meters of ocean
depth, contributing thus
to a global description
of the seasonal and interannual
variability of the upper part
of the thermohaline circulation.
Thus, within the core mission,
the main objective
focused on establishing
a coverage of a profiler
every three degrees of longitude
and three degrees of latitude
in the band of 60 degrees north
to 60 degrees south.
Although continuous advancements
in technology and hard
work of the Argo community
are allowing the original core
missions objectives to keep
growing and enabling
us to explore even further.