Hello and welcome
to the Argo Online School.
My name is Alberto
and In this course,
you will learn the basics
of the Argo program
for ocean observation.
Hi, my name is Pedro.
We assume, since you
have joined this course
that you are somewhat familiar
with the program or you have
somehow worked with data
from some observation system
for different
scientific purposes.
If this is not the case,
Don't worry.
But first of all,
let us ask you,
why do you think that we need
marine environment data?
Why is it so important
to study the ocean?
Play the next video
and find out.
As we have seen,
there's a need to understand
how the ocean works
as it's a key player
in the climate system,
but it's setting the oceans
can be a challenging task
as they cover
70% of the Earth's surface.
And not only that, the ocean
is about 4000 meters in 1999.
And you know, what is it
that was taken
by scientists to greatly improve
the collection of observation,
to increase sampling on average
in terms of time area?
That step forward with our goal.