It is said that Jason sailed
the seas on an expedition
in search of the Golden Fleece.
And that he was not alone.
He recruited the greatest
Greek heroes at the time,
including Hercules
from Boeotia,
the Dioskouroi twins from Sparta
or Kalais and Zetes
the sons of Boreas,
the North Wind.
He was a favorite
with the goddess Athena,
who had a great craftsman
build a strong and fast boat
to help them on their quest.
The Argo.
Today, an international program
collects information
from inside the ocean
using a fleet of robotic
instruments called floats
that drift with the ocean
currents and move up and down
between the surface
and a mid-water level.
The name chosen for
the program was Argo,
as the array of floats
works in partnership
with the Jason Earth
observing satellites
that measure the shape
of the ocean surface.
Each instrument spends almost
all its life below the surface
and they measure temperature
and salinity in the global ocean
providing key data
to detect changes in the ocean.
Roughly 4000 Argo floats are
currently deployed and operational
all over the Earth's oceans.
Access to data
is completely open and free,
allowing any country, any public
or private organization
and even any individual to
explore the ocean environment.