Lack of sustained observations
of the atmosphere, oceans
and land have hindered
the development and
validation of climate models.
An example from an analysis
done prior to Argo
concluded that the current
transporting heat northwards
in the Atlantic and influencing
Western European climate
had weakened by 30%
in the past decade.
This result has to be based on
just five research measurements
spread over 40 years.
Was this change part of
a trend that might lead
to a major change
in the Atlantic circulation?
Or due to natural variability
that will be reversed
in the future?
Or is it an artifact of the
limited observations?
The use of Fargo data has been
remarkably successful
in observing climate variability
and change in the ocean,
and the program is now
evolving to become part
of a more complete
observing system.