Data from the marine environment
is a truly valuable asset
fast and secured access
to the information is vital
when dealing with threat
to the marine environment,
in the development
of policies and laws
protecting vulnerable areas
in our coasts and oceans
so that we can understand
the tendencies
and are able to forecast
upcoming changes.
Unfortunately, the collection,
storage and access to marine data
has for many years
been fragmented.
There are organizations,
systems, networks
and ocean observing
programs around the world
which observe the oceans,
collect data according
to international standards
and make that information
freely available
as layers of interoperable
data and data products.
In this way, the
International Argo Program
is a component of GOOS,
a highly collaborative and
multidisciplinary observing system
built around elements
of observation,
which are administered
and finance nationally.
The main objective
of this course
is that you get used to data
from the Argo network,
from the moment it is collected
until results are obtained.