Every temperature and salinity
set of data measured
from a depth of 2000 meters
to the surface of the ocean
is called an
oceanographic profile.
This is why Argo floats
are also known as
oceanographic profilers.
Taking into account
that salinity
is obtained from measurements
of conductivity in general,
a profile of temperature and
salinity is called a CTD profile,
where C stands for conductivity,
T for temperature
and D for depth,
since in a profile, all
measurements need to show
the depth they were
collected at.
Additionally, the sensors
that measure CTD profiles
are commonly called
profiling CTDs
or simply CTDs.
The easiest way
to represent this is by
plotting the variable of any
Argo float against its depth
in such a way
that on the X axis we have
our desired variable
and on the Y axis,
the depth at which the desired
variable measurement was taken.
When reading the
oceanographic profiles,
we can obtain
relevant information
about the state
of the water column
from identifying masses of water
and monitoring
thermocline development,
to identifying ocean variability
from seasons to decades
and even quantifying
the ocean's heat content.