We are increasingly concerned
about global climate change
and its regional impacts.
Sea level is rising
at an accelerating rate
of three millimeters per year.
Arctic sea ice cover
is shrinking
and high latitude areas
are warming rapidly.
Extreme weather events
cause loss of life
and enormous burdens
on the insurance industry.
Globally, nine of the ten
warmest years since 1880
when instrumental records began,
where in the 21st century.
These effects are caused
by a mixture of
long term climate change
and natural variability.
Their impacts are,
in some cases, beneficial.
Lengthened growing seasons,
opening of Arctic
shipping routes...
And in others, adverse.
Increased coastal flooding,
extreme droughts, more frequent
heat waves and weather events
such as severe
tropical cyclones.
Understanding and eventually
predicting changes in
both the atmosphere
and ocean
are needed to guide
international actions
to optimize governments policies
and to shape
industrial strategies.
To make those predictions,
we need improved
models of climate
and of the entire Earth system,
including socioeconomic factors.