At this point, you're
probably wondering
how the observations are done.
We have seen
the cycle of an Argo float
and how it measures
oceanographic parameters.
But how does it work?
What's inside
this revolutionary device?
Standard Argo floats
are devices that
weight around 20 kilos
an are, approximately,
2 meters high.
The dive vertically by
changing their buoyancy
so they can resurface
and submerge.
There is no propulsion
system at all
so their horizontal
movements are caused
by the currents
that carry them adrift.
They consist of three subsystems.
A hydraulic system that
controls the buoyancy
through an external
inflatable bladder
so that the profiler can
resurface and submerge.
A microprocessor
that collects and stores
the data from the sensors
until it can be transmitted.
And finally,
a data transmission system
that controls communication
with satellites.