At this point,
you probably wonder
how the observations are done.
Well, the standard Argo float
mission is a ten day cycle,
with most of the floats time
spent drifting along
with deep ocean currents,
followed by taking
a series of measurements
as it moves
back up (profiles)
to the ocean surface.
Once the float is on
the surface,
it gets its location
often through GPS
and then communicates with
the satellite to send its data
and receive any
new mission instructions.
For the majority
of the Argo fleet,
this surface interval is between
15 minutes and one hour.
After that, the float sinks
to a drift depth of 1000 meters
for about nine days,
and then the float sinks to
its profile depth of 2000 meters
before slowly
rising to the surface
while measuring conductivity,
temperature and pressure.
This cycle repeats until
the float batteries die,
usually four or five years later.
Associated to the Argo network,
there is a set of mechanisms,
committees and virtual centers
that are in charge of
all the data reference tasks,
from the moment it is acquired
via satellite to its publication
in less than twelve hours
on the internet
and in the global
telecommunications network.
All the data is public and free.